Okay, now we are done with the inside of the shirt and pants.
I simply added two square-shaped panels to protect the boots.
For MD, it takes a lot of time to get started, but I hope that after watching our live stream, you will be able to use MD more systematically and learn MD better.
So I have a lot of content to talk about, and it may sound a little complicated and tiring, but I hope you can use it as soon as possible.
Because you don't want to use it in one project.
After using it in one project, you don't want to use it in one project.
After that, when you use MD, you forget how to use it.
So you need to build up a better use of it.
Next, we will teach you how to make a triangle.
First of all, we fold it in 3D creation.
After creating a version, we first draw the inner line, then fold it, and then simulate it.
I am a fashion designer.
Yes.
I just finished that part.
I am a fashion designer.
I also made an Arabian headband.
The effect I made is very good.
If I have a chance in the future, I can teach you to do it.
I like to do this kind of strange thing.
Okay, this triangle.
Fold it first, then add a fixed needle at both ends.
Then in the process of opening the simulation,
This fixed needle is used by dragging both ends.
This fixed needle is used to make a scarf.
Here we first apply a new fabric to it.
Because the fabric we used before may be, for example, the pants.
It is not easy to stretch, and it is not convenient to make a scarf.
Then we wrap it with a fixed needle on both ends.
After wrapping it, pull the back piece here.
After that, do you think I'm going to start cutting?
No.
Like this scarf.
Even if you let me do it,
I don't think I'll be able to do it.
Not to mention the big family.
Don't force yourself.
You can do it in a different way.
The difference between MD and 11 is that the UI has some differences.
In addition, there are some functions that are not the same.
For example, in the animation editor,
Because we have some other updates and optimizations for the animation editor.
So there is still a difference.
For the specific differences,
You can take a look at our new feature introduction video.
You can actually watch this kind of question with your hands.
Then let's take a look at the effect it has.
It's almost like this.
It's like this when you wrap it around your neck.
If you want to make it loose,
Then the fixed needle behind you,
Just pull it a little closer.
Or adjust it a little bit.
After reducing the particle diameter,
We'll see.
Now, if you wear this scarf to the current position,
That's about it.
Then you click it.
Look at their intersection.
This point starts to draw a line inside.
Cut this board.
Actually, if you make a triangle,
There was also in the previous teaching video.
So if you don't know how to do it,
Of course, we can show it to you in the live broadcast.
If it's more detailed and clearer,
You can take a look at that video.
Of course, the style here is simpler than that of the previous video.
Because here we don't need to make a very, very detailed triangle.
Okay.
Then here,
I'm going to show you how to make a triangle.
Okay.
Then here,
You can see that I finally put it on both ends.
Wait a minute.
It's going to be a knot.
That's the knot.
After the knot,
Aren't there going to be two little corners coming out?
I'm going to cut off the little corner.
And then I'm going to put it on its main body.
The triangle of the body itself.
The two ends are mixed together.
This way, it's easier to control this triangle.
If you want it to be a little longer,
You just make this width a little wider.
It will naturally be long enough.
It will sink down.
You know?
Okay.
Then we counter-activate the collar.
For the triangle,
We'll have to make further adjustments later.
Okay.
Next is to make a vest.
In fact, in the last video of making a vest,
We've already talked about it.
I usually just copy and paste the inner layer of the shirt.
Then increase its shrink rate to 120%.
This way, it's a little wider than the inside of the vest.
And then I'll give it a layer.
It's going to come out soon.
After it comes out,
We're going to use the buttonhole tool.
Send the two sides together.
After that, we'll simulate it again.
Okay.
After the simulation,
It's a little bit unstable.
It's okay.
Let's return its shrink rate to 100.
Because our shrink rate was 120 before.
Now we're going to return the shrink rate to 100.
It's normal.
This is the result of being cautious.
And then?
Because now we've used layers.
Quickly put on the clothes.
But the collar here,
Generally,
The collar will be under the collar of the inner layer of the shirt.
Okay.
Then we can cut the collar first.
Then we can put it through the layer.
If you cut the collar,
Here we use the 3D drawing tool.
Directly on the board.
Click on the board.
Then click along the cut position.
Create a 3D line.
Then on the basis of these 3D lines.
We go to create the inner line.
You can cut the board.
This specific operation method.
You can watch the last video of the suit.
But I'm almost there.
You can see it here.
You probably know.
Draw in 3D space first.
The part you want to cut.
Then go to the 2D window.
Use the inner line tool to cut.
Or you can directly in the 3D window.
Use the 3D drawing tool to edit.
Select the middle line.
Right click.
Cut.
It can also be cut.
There will be a screen.
Okay.
In the 3D space.
We cut these boards.
In the 2D window.
After you cut the board.
We'll delete the excess boards.
Now he's a maja.
So sometimes you think.
If the 2D window is not very intuitive.
You can just cut it in the 3D window.
Then we return the layer to zero.
Then the layer here from the collar.
Increase to 1.
How to use the layer function.
If you don't know.
You can go to the skill sharing.
Find the layer video.
Okay.
After the simulation is stable.
Return the layer to zero.
Then the layer is automatically.
In the collar.
Because the collar is a separate version.
It's a separate version of the big body.
So we just need to adjust the collar.
This clothes will be stuck in the collar.
Okay.
After that, adjust the position of the button.
Because it also has some conflicts with the button inside.
We will manually adjust it.
Okay.
And then like.
For the collar.
I will add another layer of the collar.
Because.
In this way.
We can go through.
Let the outer layer of the collar.
There is a difference in the shrinkage.
For example, the outer collar.
Its shrinkage is relatively large.
Then it is sewn on the inner layer of the collar.
This way.
Can form more wrinkles through the difference between the inside and the outside.
Here.
Because we just used the outer layer of the collar.
So everyone.
Be sure to pay attention to it when you are usually on the collar.
The panel is divided into the outer and inner layers of the collar.
If the panel chooses the outer layer of the collar.
This panel.
When the collar is outside.
Once there is a gap with other panels.
Then it will be unstable.
If you encounter such a situation.
You just activate the panel to simulate with it.
Let it simulate stability.
For example, like here.
I freeze the collar here.
So when the outer layer of the collar is outside.
Its own space is not enough.
If I don't untie it.
It will always be unstable.
When you encounter such a situation.
You just untie this panel.
Let's simulate together.
If you have any questions about 10WMD.
You can also ask in the bulletin board.
Or you can put our live broadcast room.
Share it in your group.
Let more friends come together.
Watch our video.
Let's discuss our live broadcast together.
Here you can see.
Through different tail shrinkage.
For example, my outer panel.
May use a higher tail shrinkage.
It will produce more wrinkles.
Or a little more.
Did you see it?
When I adjust the tail shrinkage to 102.
It is longer than the inner panel.
In this way.
There will be more wrinkles.
So this is why.
We usually.
In the process of normal production.
I like to do it.
Double-layer structure.
That's why.
I used to be a CLO.
CLO team.
Then.
Then I used CLO first.
Then MD.
I've been in the company for about five years.
Well.
Okay.
Then we use the inner line.
Make the edge of the wrinkle.
Everyone knows.
When we are on the Cologne layer.
The inner line will automatically produce the wrinkle line.
If you are Cologne first.
Then draw the inner line.
He can't do it.
Form a wrinkle line directly between the inner line.
At this time.
You have to do it manually.
So when you are on the Cologne layer.
You have to think about your order first.
If you want to do this.
The effect of having a wrinkle line to cut.
Or the inner line.
You draw the inner line first.
Then it will be more convenient on the Cologne layer.
The function of CLO and MD.
It doesn't exist.
Which one is more.
Which one is less.
But we are targeting the customer group.
It's different.
CLO's customer group.
Is.
The clothing industry.
MD's customer group.
Is.
The CG industry.
CLO's users.
Are more inclined to.
One software.
Can accumulate.
Most of them.
The effect.
And content.
Can produce.
Directly.
This.
Effective picture.
These.
So.
CLO will have these.
And.
MD's users.
Will hope.
MD is their workflow.
One of them.
So.
The function.
In MD.
More.
Connect other software.
Or.
The.
Users.
They.
Need.
Some.
Is.
3D industry.
Those.
Users.
They.
Need.
The function.
This.
Still.
Some.
Different.
Then.
We.
Freeze.
The.
These.
Pages.
Activate.
Triangles.
Let's simulate.
It.
Is.
Not.
Our.
Triangles.
It.
Is.
Foldable.
So.
If.
You.
Directly.
Use.
The.
Level.
To.
Adjust.
It.
First.
Because.
It.
Is.
Foldable.
The.
Situation.
That.
It.
To.
Identify.
The.
Sound.
It.
Fades.
Into.
A.
Fader.
This.
Is.
The.
Here.
Can.
See.
It.
Is.
Different.
From.
The.
Fader.
A.
Flight.
It.
Is.
Different.
From.
Here.
Is.
make sure that the knot is as narrow as possible.
Or we can tighten it up by adding the elastic ratio.
We need to tighten this part first,
and then put the knotted strip near this position,
and then wrap the knot with a wrapped sheet.
This way we can make a stabilizer,
and the knot will be tight again.
We won't tie the knot manually,
because it will be unstable if we tie the knot manually.
You can't control the number of knots in the knot,
so we will make some substitutions.
Do you understand?
We need to add some pins here,
and then naturally simulate the knot,
and then fix them on both sides.
Fix the knot here, and fix it here,
so that it forms this kind of knot,
and we can make it stand out.
Although it looks a little strange,
you will know why we do this when we put it on later.
I don't know if you guys have ever made a scarf
in Marvelous Designer,
or made gloves and hats.
Have you ever done it?
We add a elastic in the middle of this piece,
and let it tighten up.
Try to make these pieces as close as possible.
Then we are going to start making
the ring that we are going to use to tighten it up.
We first draw a rectangle,
and then add a line in the middle
to fold this piece.
Because if you don't fold the piece first,
but just sew it up and down,
then the function of the sewing line
plus the function of gravity
will cause this ring to twist or turn.
Wow, Fat Tiger, you are amazing.
You have never seen a tutorial before,
but you have made a complicated bag.
You are very confident.
After we fold it up,
let's simulate it.
Let this piece form a ring.
After forming a ring,
we can harden the piece.
After hardening the piece,
it will be rounder.
We drag the piece by hand
to form a rounder ring.
This is the same principle as the butterfly knot.
Yes, it is the same principle as the butterfly knot.
Yes.
But here,
we are going to be lazy.
We don't need to sew up the piece.
Because later,
we will tighten these two pieces
little by little through the knot.
So here,
we don't need to sew it up.
Because if you sew it up,
it may be a little unstable.
Let's try to make it rounder
when we simulate it in 3D space.
We can wrap the butterfly knot
and the triangle itself.
After wrapping it up,
you can see that
I made some fixed needles.
When we simulate this kind of butterfly knot,
we first make it
in the shape of a 1.
Then,
we can make it
in the shape of a 1.
We make it in the shape of a 1.
Don't let it fall off naturally.
Okay.
After we pass through this ring,
we can start to
tighten the ring little by little.
First,
we can tighten the knot
little by little.
Then,
we can untie the hardening.
we can tighten the knot
little by little.
If you do it here,
you need to be a little patient.
Because the knot is a whole.
Although the knot is a small piece,
it needs to bear
so much force
from so many pieces.
So,
when we do it,
we must ensure
that it is stable.
So,
when we untie the knot,
we will lower the strength of the
particle
a little bit.
Also,
we need to tighten the thread.
Tightening the thread
because our knot
is already very close to the thread.
If we
cut the knot
directly,
If we cut the knot
for example,
you move this thread
to tighten it,
it will apply
the function of the thread
to the knot.
The thread
is all straight.
It is not a straight line.
It will not bend
along the original curve.
It will not bend along the original curve.
So sometimes
after you adjust it,
the opening
may be too big.
We will adjust it
with the torsion
to ensure
that it is
always a closed ring.
to ensure that it is always a closed ring.
It does not need
to apply
the stretching of the thread 1.
to apply the stretching of the thread 1.
This
is easier to control.
Understand?
So,
when we are already
relatively tight,
you can see
that at this moment
we have removed
the fixed thread.
These sheets
will
to create some deformations in the ring.
At this point, it will be inappropriate to change the length of the ring.
We will then adjust its
gold-like shrinkage or tail-like shrinkage,
and let it shrink up.
Try to ensure its stability.
Because of this fabric,
we can finally turn this fabric into transparent,
and then make an external structure in the middle of it,
or replace it with other fabrics,
to replace the complicated position in the middle.
So we just need to ensure that it is stable now.
Do you understand?
Listen to the
You are now using an external force
to tighten it up in the middle.
This is the most important.
We can see that if we use the shrink to shrink the area,
it will be more stable.
It is not as unstable as changing the plate.
Are you sound to sleepy?
Get up!
Give me a 3 o'clock.
Here, because to prevent the hair style to fall down later,
we need to stretch this knot.
So we use a pincer needle
to pull the edge of the neck down.
And we need to tighten this knot.
So we use a pincer needle
to tighten the neck down.
and tighten this knot.
So we use a pincer needle
so that the overall shape will be more stable in the current position.
Wake up, wake up, wake up.
Now let's go back to the front.
The physical properties that I applied to the vest here are wool,
because I want its vest to be a little thick.
Here, when I was making this inner line strip,
I suddenly found that I missed one.
So I made another one here.
After making one, there is a function to align the inner line here.
I don't know if you have noticed it.
We have to align the inner line to the inner line.
In this way, you can quickly align the inner line to the position of the inner line.
Oh, no.
It's a little bit similar to the outer line of the panel.
After that, I made the belt for the bullet.
I almost said the belt for the bullet.
The belt for the bullet.
And then I pasted it in the 3D container and turned it over on the surface.
So you can arrange the two belts very quickly.
Then use the sewing line.
If you think you can't distinguish the right and the wrong in the 2D window,
you can choose the 3D sewing line tool in the 3D space.
Click.
Pay attention to the direction of the click.
The bullet for the belt.
Oh, the belt for the bullet.
The belt for the bullet.
After making this belt,
I used a new fabric for it.
I used Trimful Leather for this fabric.
The fabric of the belt.
The fabric of the leather.
This fabric has a higher bending strength.
So it has the texture of leather.
It's not easy to get creases.
Even if there is a crease, it's a big piece.
Then because of this fabric, its bending strength is too high.
When the bending strength is very high, this fabric does not stick to the body.
It's easy to feel that it's very, very hard.
It doesn't stick to the body.
So let's reduce it first.
Reduce its bending strength so that it can stick to the body.
Let's take a look again.
Before, you see, is it very hard like this?
Right?
It's all bent here.
Then you reduce the bending strength and then simulate it.
You see, it's a little bit close.
It won't be that hard.
OK, OK.
Then to prevent the belt from slipping,
we use a sewing needle to fix its point here.
Here, too.
Let's take a look.
Now we've only talked about half of it.
Family, wake up.
Simulate it.
When you simulate it, drag the plate off manually.
Now the part we're going to do is actually this part.
The part where the bullet is placed.
Do you understand?
It's OK.
When you're done with the nucleic acid,
come back and see.
I should still be live.
OK.
Then we draw the inner line.
Make a small bag for it here.
Draw two inner lines to fix the position.
OK.
Then draw another inner line.
Take a look.
It's almost like a little bag.
Then use the hook and loop tool to select all the lines of the bag.
Then right-click to select the hook and loop panel.
This way, you can extract the small part of the middle panel.
Expand with panel outline.
Remember to hook here to create the inner line.
Because we're going to fold these inner lines later.
Then expand the number to choose 2.
The border is the border on the side.
Remember the side angle here.
We're going to choose 5 corners.
Can you see it?
It's not going to be linked together.
It's called 5 corners.
In this case,
whether you choose perpendicular or extend,
it's the same.
Just remember to choose 5 corners.
Because we're going to sew up here later.
It's like folding a paper box.
OK.
Then we sew up between the panels.
When we used the line to sew up just now,
did you see that we used the line to sew up
a whole section?
Because the inner line here hasn't been cut off yet.
Our belt hasn't been cut off yet.
So we're going to cut it off first.
Right-click to select align to the outline line above
and add a point.
Then you can use the line sewing tool to sew it up.
Because we already have a break in the middle.
Not finished is not broadcasted.
The screen is placed in B station,
not WeChat public number.
It's B station.
OK.
Then we print the panel.
Let it fold up quickly.
OK.
Simulate.
Reset print.
OK.
Because the fabric we used just now
is the fabric of the leather fabric.
The leather fabric itself is relatively hard.
Plus the panels here
are sewed up between the panels.
In the case of the default custom angle,
the leather fabric will be like this.
When it is connected,
it is also very difficult to bend.
So it will give some strength to this side.
Let this box,
this little bag,
its folding is very,
its folding is not very smooth.
So,
in this case,
we first have to set it up.
This sewing line,
the type of sewing line,
choose TURN,
not Custom Angle.
So they can identify it.
These two panels are folded and sewed up.
Yes.
There will be sound in the recording of the live broadcast.
Don't scare me.
There should be sound.
You can hear me talking.
There is sound when it is recorded.
Where did I just talk about?
Just now our edge is still very hard.
Its,
because these two panels,
it just used the default sewing line type,
Custom Angle.
Now let's take a look again.
Now we have changed to TURN.
After that,
the system will identify that this little bag and the belt are in two layers.
Because the bag is on the outside layer and the belt is inside.
After this identification,
it will not be like before.
There is a very serious stretch problem.
OK,
then we are going to do the effect of this pocket fold.
What does the effect of this pocket fold mean?
It means,
it means that this pocket will fold in.
Here we use the fold tool,
click,
then double click,
then click to confirm.
This way,
the system will,
this fold arrangement,
fold,
ah,
this is the fold and fold function,
to automatically apply the fold angle to the inner line.
After we open the simulation,
this pocket will automatically fold.
There is no change in the sound.
Huh?
Is there a change in the sound?
Then use,
uh,
editor,
or use the creative line folding tool to fold it.
OK,
after the seam is done,
this little pocket will be done.
In fact,
this is just to simply tell you
to be more sensitive and aware of our previous folding,
folding and folding tools.
You should have seen that
I usually do live broadcasts for you.
Basically,
I will mention a lot of tools in the last video.
I will mention this video again.
Because we don't use these tools repeatedly,
it is easy to forget the existence of these tools.
So here we add another foldable content.
OK,
then draw a rectangular board for it,
as its small pocket lid.
That's it.
OK,
we'll skip this quickly.
then through the inner line,
you can move the inner line,
you can move the position of the pocket.
OK,
then finally,
you can add this kowen and knurl,
then tie them together.
See,
this is not a skill,
oh,
it's not a skill,
it's not a function I can remember,
so you must use it frequently,
so you know and remember these functions when you use it frequently.
Wait a minute,
I drink a water.
OK,
so then,
I will show you how to use it in detail.
You have to use your fingers to mark.
And
Let me have a sip of water.
Here you can see that the particle diameter has been reduced.
Some children used to say,
why does my corner have such a blank position?
This is because your particle diameter is not enough.
This is because our grid surface is all triangular or quadrilateral.
Look at the curve here.
To form such a curve,
it must have a lot of grid numbers.
When the particle diameter is 20 or 15,
the edge of this grid is already this wide.
It can't form such a thin curve.
So in this case,
we need to reduce the particle diameter
so that it has as many grid numbers as possible.
Next, let's do the middle part of the bullet.
First,
let's draw the shape of the cut in the middle.
Then,
let's make a cut.
let's choose the interval of the internal line.
Then,
let's not select the internal line extension.
Let's remove this part in the middle.
Let's make the internal line extension.
Okay,
after drawing all these segment lines,
we can start to choose the internal line in the curve.
Let's make these segment lines.
These are the segment lines where each bullet can be placed.
Then, let's choose to align to the internal line.
In this way,
we have already made the internal line in the middle of the bullet.
Just manually draw these internal lines.
Hello, hello, hello, hello.
Are you all awake?
Then, let's draw the outer part of the column.
Here, the outer part of the column is for,
because when we draw the column in the panel,
the line will automatically form.
In other words,
we don't need to manually add the line between the panel and the panel,
and the line between the line and the line.
Or we can let some lines,
they will automatically form the line.
Because we are going to make it here later.
In the end,
this panel is made by their length difference.
You can take a look.
Look,
the overall length of this panel
is longer than these mountains.
Do you see it?
In this way,
there is such a curved part.
So, we are going to let them automatically have the line.
Then, we are going to use the outer part of the column here.
OK.
After the column is finished,
we delete the excess panels,
and only keep the middle ones.
OK.
Later, I will randomly draw the questions
from my friends.
I am going to make sure that you are awake.
Don't be fooled by me.
You are still sleeping while watching the live broadcast.
Then, let's sew the middle line
between the inner line and the inner line.
Because just now,
I cut off the panel here.
When you cut off the panel,
if the inner line of the original line
and the other inner line of this panel
have the sewing line,
after you cut it off,
they automatically identify as two panels.
The sewing line will be automatically canceled.
So, you have to manually fill the sewing line.
Of course, these are very simple.
You will find that there is a problem
during the operation.
OK.
When sewing here,
you have to pay attention.
Because we have a cut point here,
and there is no cut point here.
So, we use the free sewing tool
to sew it.
OK.
Why do you use a sewing machine?
Well,
there is a way.
We have,
I used to have a live broadcast.
Although we don't have a fixed time,
we usually prepare a live broadcast
when we have time.
For example,
there is a live broadcast every month.
It will happen every month
or every half month.
Move this panel to the outside,
then, we will simulate it
and sew it together.
I don't know if you have noticed, but the wrinkle of the leather fabric itself is not very obvious.
Because its bending strength is large, it is not easy to bend, and even if there is a difference in length, it is not easy to be reflected in the shape of the wrinkle.
So even if you reduce the particle diameter, it still has no wrinkle.
This is why we need to apply another fabric to it when making the outer version, not the leather fabric.
You see, the leather fabric uses the wrinkle-strength attribute, and the outer fabric uses the default fabric.
After selecting the middle version, the center of the double machine selection frame can be selected.
After selecting the center, all the frames will be in orange color.
If we move the selection frame, it will be projected with the center of the version.
Let's see, in case you don't know, after selecting the frame and selection version, the double machine will turn on the center point.
When you don't move the center point, it is the center of the version.
your rotation is based on the center point.
Otherwise, in normal situations,
your rotation is based on the point you are dragging now.
Do you see it?
The two center points are rotated based on the center point.
The rotation is also based on the center point.
Then the center point can be moved.
For example, you can move to this corner.
The rotation of the center point is based on the center point.
Or the rotation of the center point is based on the center point.
Then what can we do?
For example, you can move the center point to another position.
Then you can rotate the center point like this.
I don't know how it works.
But I will teach you first.
There is nothing wrong with it.
This is the center point.
Then we can make this board a little longer.
Such a grid is a little bigger than the original one.
It naturally forms a wave.
Do you see it?
Because we only sew the inner line.
The two sides are open.
This is how the egg shell part is formed.
It's like this.
Because only the center of the inner line is sewn.
Then,
If we feel that its volume is not enough,
If we make this board longer,
Then you will see that there is a gap between it and the belt.
If you directly simulate this gap,
It must be unstable.
So you need to select the right arrow of this board and add it to the outside.
Let it automatically add to the outside of the board that it rejects.
At this time, we simulate that it is stable.
Understand?
Do you understand?
Do you understand, family?
Let me take a look at it.
I can't change it directly because there are too many boards here.
If we change it, it will not be stable.
That is to say, if you
Because you put this board directly,
It's a direct extension of the grid.
It will definitely be different from the other boards.
That's right.
So we just add it directly to the outside.
Add it to, you see, for example, like here, we add it to the sky, or we can't just show it here.
If you add it directly to the outside, it will be added according to the current sewed version of it.
What is this? Can't you understand?
Well, no, I still have to show it to you.
Let me find the half of the project that I did before.
Let me see, it should be this project.
Okay, let's say we've done this part now.
And then if we go straight to the sewing,
we can see that there is a gap between the two parts on this side.
It will have a gap with this model.
At this time, if we simulate it directly, first of all, it will be a little unstable.
Can you see it? It will shake like this, not stable, right?
In this case, we just add it to the outside.
Hey, you can't just do that.
I have to go back to just now.
For example, let's shrink it a little bit.
Then add it to the outside.
Okay, is it very neat now?
Because its sewing line is only related to this part.
Let's take a look at the sewing line.
It is only sewed together with this version.
If you add it to the outside, it is also a very neat arrangement.
Then turn on the simulation.
It will be like this.
Then you see.
At this time, is it a little unstable when it is twisted?
Because it is frozen with its sewing line.
At this time, we will turn off the collision.
Then reset the 3D position.
After that, it will no longer be unstable.
We also talked about this in the first half of the course.
Now do you understand?
If you add it to the outside,
it will only add the sewing line along the current sewing line to the outside of the board it is sewing.
Or inside.
For example,
now this board only has a sewing line on the inner layer.
It only has a sewing relationship here.
Then we choose to add it to the outside.
It will add this board to the outside of the board it is sewing.
If it sews a lot of boards at the same time,
it will add the sewing line to the outside.
Understand?
Then if you choose to add it to the side,
it will add it to the side of the board.
Then there must be a problem with the grid.
An unstable problem.
If you choose to add it to the inside,
see?
It is neatly arranged inside the board that it is sewing.
Inside.
See?
Add it to the outside.
It's outside.
Add it to the inside.
It's inside.
Understand?
Yes.
The reason it becomes flat
is because it is flat with the board it is sewing.
Understand?
Okay, let's take a look again.
For example, your board is like this.
Wait a minute.
For example, I have a board here.
Right?
Okay.
Then find a board
and sew it together with it.
Okay, add it to the outside.
It will turn over like this.
Add it to the inside.
It will turn to the other side.
Add it to the side.
It will turn to the bottom.
Because your sewing line only has this one sewing line.
If we add another sewing line at this time,
for example, our sewing line relationship changes.
For example, our sewing line is sewn like this.
Okay.
At this time,
if you add it to the outside,
it will be sewn like this.
Add it to the inside.
It will be sewn like this.
See?
It is front to front.
It is based on your sewing line.
If your two sewing lines are lined up like this,
then when you add it to the outside,
it will be the same.
If your sewing line is not the same,
but sewn like this,
it means that you are the side sewing.
See?
If they are sewn like this,
then when you add it to the outside,
it will turn over.
Do you know?
Because in order for your sewing line to be sewn together,
it has to turn over.
If you add it to the inside,
it will turn inside.
Then if you add it to the side,
it is the correct position to sew.
Do you understand?
Will the long version not be flat?
This is based on your sewing line.
Do you know?
Because the sewing line we created before
is well-matched on each side,
and it is well-matched on the inside.
The only thing that is related to the sewing line
is this version.
This version is flat.
When you add it to the outside
in a flat situation,
it is also flat.
But at this time,
if we have some strange operations
on this version,
for example,
in my 3D space,
it is not flat itself.
Then when you create a sewing line,
and then choose to add it to the outside,
it is now very flat.
It doesn't matter.
But if this version
itself has some grid,
that is,
unstable problems,
it may have some problems.
For example,
because it is difficult for me to reproduce this kind of strange problem,
you know,
add it to the outside.
You see,
for example,
at this time,
the whole version is relatively long.
See?
Is this version longer than this version?
At this time,
if you add it to the outside,
it will definitely have some grid breakage problems.
Because it has to adapt to this version.
But if you simulate it,
it will still stabilize.
Do you understand?
Including adding it to the inside,
it is the same.
It is the same in the inside.
It is a grid.
Although it looks like this grid,
but after you simulate it,
it is still stable.
Understand?
It is just a close-up of another version.
So sometimes you have to pay attention.
For example,
in case you add this function,
it sewed two panels at the same time.
Then when you add it to the outside,
it will be sewed by these two panels at the same time.
If it is a pair,
you will add it to the outside directly.
It will be sewed by two parts at the same time.
Do you understand?
I didn't expect you to use this function.
This function is quite common.
It is used to arrange the panels quickly.
I like this function.
Next, let's deal with the body band.
If you sew the hem by hand,
maybe it will take some time.
may take some time.
It has unique sewing lines
Plus the addition function
makes the squared posso desperate.
Next, let's look at the waist belt.
This part l셔야 pass close the bodyl
This part l Эм
That part is supposed...
to be a more λ.
That part is supposed to be a long part.
and then move this point out, and this point out, and then sew them together, it's a close-knit.
The belt of the waistband is one long and one short, what are you talking about?
Are you talking about this?
Is this one long and one short?
The difference between them is that each of them is lined up,
so it's just that each of them, it's equivalent to putting every small rectangle into a small rectangle.
So it won't be unstable, understand?
Okay, so now we've moved this point up, and now it's close-knit.
But although the belt looks close-knit,
is it a shoulder here?
It's also a shoulder here, so we're going to turn it into a flat corner.
It looks more normal.
In order to make sure that it doesn't affect the other panels,
we're going to press the X button here, click, and add some separation points,
keeping the top part of it from being affected.
Then we use the edit panel tool to adjust this curve,
adjust it to 90 degrees on both sides, see?
Both sides are 90 degrees, so that they are pinned together, which is a straight corner.
And then if this corner is relatively small,
we use the editor tool to turn it into a continuous curve.
Here as well, turn it into a continuous curve,
and then simulate it.
Okay, if this corner is more sharp,
we're going to move it back a little bit.
And then through this method,
you can make this panel here more close-knit,
and it looks more like a continuous curve when it's pinned together.
Understand?
It's equivalent to a slight change,
so you can change the panel at this connection point
so that it can be attached here.
Because if you have two straight, rectangular panels,
it must be one end,
that is, one end is just right to be attached,
but the other end will be long.
So just turn this panel into a curve like this,
like a hook.
Um, icon.
Wait a minute.
Okay.
Then we're going to make this belt.
Let's talk about the belt a little bit faster.
Because the bag part is actually not very difficult.
Let's draw two rectangles first.
And then,
remember here,
we put this hanger at the beginning,
this little hanger panel of the belt.
Before that,
let's take the belt out of here manually.
Look,
when we simulate,
when we start the simulation,
we manually drag it out,
reserve this part of the space,
and then freeze this panel.
After freezing,
put these two panels on it.
After putting it on,
let's simulate it again.
Okay.
After simulation,
sew the bottom up.
That's it.
Um,
um,
oh,
sewing.
After sewing,
this belt panel in the activation,
it will naturally put this,
uh,
is to press back the body part.
This is also more convenient.
It's also more stable.
Just,
uh,
because if you use the layer directly,
plus there is a button here,
this belt,
it may have problems with recognition.
So,
so let's do it manually.
That is,
you have to,
uh,
hang the position of this bag belt.
Just pull it out first.
Okay,
then do this gun belt.
Ah,
what does the gun belt actually say?
Just put,
ah,
this is the bag with the gun.
This little bag.
Ah,
we just finished this piece.
Now we are going to do this part.
In fact,
the gun belt is also a similar method.
You can refer to it.
Okay,
draw a rectangle first.
Well,
when we are doing it,
you can't predict this version.
What is the original body like?
You draw a rectangle first,
and then,
uh,
use the editor to select a line.
When,
you can shrink it inward.
Then,
uh,
how come there are two lines in this section?
It came again yesterday.
Then sew it.
Adjust the shape of this whole thing.
Then we sew it again.
Oh,
when I was actually making a version,
I didn't react at first.
I can't figure out what this version looks like.
I also draw a rectangle first.
Then,
change it little by little.
After sewing,
uh,
copy and paste a version.
Uh,
then shrink this version a little bit.
After shrinking it a little bit,
put it in a 3D space.
After putting it in,
uh,
let's do it manually.
Uh,
almost imagine what it looks like when it overlaps.
Okay,
let's make up the side of it again.
This board.
In fact,
when you put it in a 3D space,
it's already,
uh,
I can feel it.
If there is a board on the side of it,
connect these two boards together,
it should also be a T-shape.
Do you understand?
Well,
you see,
this is an oblique.
This is flat.
It's oblique.
So it's a bit like a T-shape.
These two lines are parallel.
Then there are two oblique lines here.
So when I'm creating a board,
I also
will observe it in the 3D window
and in the 2D window.
To decide how to create this board.
So we're going to draw a board now.
The overall length of this board
and this longer board are equal in length.
Then we change one end of it
to be as long as the short board.
We can directly change the length of this line
by changing the length tool.
Okay.
Now we have a T-shape.
Then we sew this T-shape
to the side of these two boards.
Do you understand?
Hello?
Wake up, wake up.
After I sew it here,
press Ctrl D
to create a parallel board
and place it in the 3D space.
Okay, okay, okay.
Okay, okay.
Have you ever made a bag in MD?
Or a small bag like this one?
Have you?
If you need it,
you can tell me.
In the future,
we can make a video
about how to make a bag.
Because when I made it myself,
I actually think that making a bag
is almost the same as turning it over and over again.
I feel that it's not too much different.
It doesn't have a special place to talk about.
The most important thing is to set the angle of folding.
Then I will use leather fabric for this side.
Then I will reduce its bending strength a little bit more.
So that it is not so easy to make a fold.
But you also have a certain
angle of folding.
It's not too much bending.
It's just that there's still a feeling of folding.
Oh, you're all in a hurry.
Okay, okay, okay.
I understand.
Okay, like this.
We will use the folding angle of the sewing line.
The folding angle
is actually more than the folding angle of the inner line.
Here, I will remind you again.
What is the folding angle?
In case there are new friends who don't know.
Anyway, the folding angle is like this.
For example, we now have a board.
Then we fix it.
After fixing it,
we draw an inner line in the middle.
Then we don't operate now.
Let me ask.
If I want this inner line
to protrude outwards on the front of this inner line,
how much should I set its folding angle?
If I want it to protrude outwards
on the front of this board,
how much is the folding angle of this inner line?
Is there anyone who can tell me?
That's right.
Tiffany's milk bottle is right.
It's not greater than 180 degrees.
Look, look.
I forgot it again.
So I will forget it if I don't repeat it.
It's less than 180 degrees.
Then it will protrude outwards on the front of this inner line.
Can you see it?
What if I want it to bend inwards?
From the front,
if it bends inwards,
how much should I set it?
You are too smart.
Tiffany's milk bottle.
If I want it to bend inwards,
what should I set this value to?
Yes, it's greater than 180 degrees.
360 degrees.
It bends inwards.
Can you see it?
In other words,
if you look at it from the back,
if we turn it over,
if we look at it from the back,
360 degrees is
protruding outwards on the back.
If it bends inwards,
it bends inwards on the back.
Do you know?
So,
this kind of knowledge
is to keep looking back.
Okay,
let's go back to this version.
Because of this inner-layer version,
we just turned it over on the surface.
So now the whole surface of it
is connected.
Its direction of discovery is connected.
Right?
It's all on one side.
Okay,
in this case,
if I,
because the Frenzy line
can also be set
from a folding angle.
I'm using Marvelous.
It's 11.
Because the Frenzy line
can also be set from a folding angle.
In this case,
we can also
see it as an inner-layer
to set a folding angle
and let it fold up.
For example, 90 degrees.
Look,
I set it to 90 degrees here,
and it folds up immediately.
Do you see it?
It will form
a deeper folding angle.
It's similar to the inner-layer.
It's just a reminder
not to forget it.
The Frenzy line
also has a folding angle to use.
After that,
we can make a T-shape
at the bottom of it.
Okay,
we just put it together
and then
compare it.
Take a look
and you will know
that we need to make
another T-shape
here.
Okay,
you can also
reply to the comments
if you have any questions.
Okay,
thank you.
Thank you.
Okay.
Can't be 잡ed.
Okay,
here
you can see
I have a function
toada
on it.
Once you select a T-shape,
it will cause
a function called
moving-in-ta 눈
to-girl- elles'
t-shape function.
By selecting this function,
you can place the patrol
automatically
near to the while-tsu
or folks'
T-shape,
and you don't have to use
görable in- Kong
to move-in-a-girl-ells'.
Do you understand?
This is also
an eventual
Because sometimes there are some panels that are blocked, or the newly created panels,
once there are more panels, then sometimes the position of the panels will be relatively far.
It's also relatively far in 3D space, and if it's inconvenient to drag and drop,
one is to use the positioning function, and the other is to use the panel function that can be moved to the seam.
Then we draw another panel, and then draw some internal lines to be separated.
When adding this button, click the triangle in the lower right corner of the button window,
and you can choose other types of buttons in it.
I chose a hat here.
Then select the button after moving the button,
and then select the button.
After selecting the button, you can rotate these buttons in the parameter editor.
Because imagine that the angle of the button is different,
so we don't adjust it in the button project column,
but we have to use the move button tool to select the button,
and then adjust the angle of each button separately.
So sometimes people will find it strange,
why my button properties can also be selected by the button properties adjustment here,
there are also other properties in the parameter editor window after selecting the button.
This is because they are different contents.
Here, it is related to the type of this button,
such as the diameter of this button, or its height, and its color.
But if you select a single button, you can adjust its angle.
Do you understand?
So everyone,
Since people are usually using MD,
it must mean that,
oh you see,
I chose this kind of button here,
and the button below this window is the button project,
that means that different styles of buttons,
can adjust its specifications and attributes below.
Do you understand?
It's the same as the option of the selection of the clothes just now,
The options are different for each version.
Because you usually use MD,
it doesn't mean that the main page uses MD.
So there is a lot of knowledge.
If you are a newcomer,
we have to constantly emphasize
to help you deepen these impressions.
After we have adjusted it like this,
sometimes people will say,
oh, why is this button
floating outside the version?
First of all, there is a thing called the length of the line.
The length of this line is to control the distance
between the button and the button face.
This value can be set to a negative value.
When you set it to a negative value,
the button will stick to the inside of this version.
But did you find that
when we turn on the simulation,
this button will bounce out
because we turn on the simulation
and there is a conflict between the button and the button face?
The button face will also have bumps around it.
It has bumps with the version.
So if you want it to have no bumps,
you have to turn off the conflict.
Do you understand?
Because you see,
it's the same as when we choose the weight.
Note that this is also using
the move button tool.
Because you don't want to,
usually when we use it,
we don't say that the whole button
type has conflicts or no conflicts.
We usually choose these buttons
separately.
After that,
we choose whether or not there is a conflict.
So this function is placed in a specific button.
You have to choose this button
to see these attributes
in the simulation machine.
Do you understand?
So you have to set it to no conflicts.
In this way,
you can set the length of the line.
When the length of the line is set to negative,
it will be in this version.
So the function of the length of the line
has been told to everyone.
In addition to the length of our button,
there is a length of the line.
There is also a length of the line of the seam.
Through the length of the line,
you can set a point to another point.
What is the distance between them?
So if the length of the button line
is set to a positive value
and is relatively large,
this button will be farther away
from the point where you put the button.
Let's show it again.
I'm afraid you might forget.
This thing looks a little closed.
Delete it here.
For example,
we have a button
on this board.
Then select the move button tool.
Set the length of the line here.
For example, it is 10.
Look, it will.
If we freeze this board,
freeze this board,
and do it,
we can control the distance from the bottom of the board.
See?
The distance between the lines
will be fixed.
When you do special effects,
or when the whole costume is thick,
you may need to set the length of the line
to make the button
out of the way.
It is the same as the length of the line
set by the sewing machine.
Because the button you put on
is actually set by the middle of the button.
So the length of the line
is the same as the length of the line
set by the sewing machine.
It is set
because the button you put on
from the center of the button to the point where you click.
This is why when we self-define the button,
let's talk a little bit more about this.
When we self-define the button,
the teacher will say that you have to put the button to the right side of the Y-axis.
In fact, you need to apply the coordinates in MD.
Because when you add the button,
it has already imagined this side as the floor of MD.
So it has to face up.
It is equivalent to putting the button like this.
If you imagine this thing as the ground,
your button has to be placed on it like this.
And the length of the line,
each button has its own length of line.
This is the height of the button from the ground.
So you are outside,
that is,
the button we choose
When you self-define the button,
there is a plus sign here.
You can self-define the button.
Click it,
it will pop up a button.
You can use your own model
in the form of such a button,
put it in MD.
If you want to self-define it,
it is recommended that your OBJ is first poured into MD.
Apply the coordinates of MD,
put it in the center of the coordinates,
face up,
put it on the ground,
and then pour it out again.
When pouring out,
remember that the unit is mm.
Because MD,
although you can choose the unit of the whole system
in the settings and user self-defining,
but like this button,
its unit is best to be unified to mm first,
and then use it after unifying the unit of your OBJ model to mm.
Otherwise, it may have some broken problems,
because its unit is different.
Understand?
Next, we will do the belt part.
For the belt,
the middle panel
is wider than the actual panel.
Can you see it?
The panel is wider than the actual panel.
In this way, it can be rolled up,
and there will be a gap in the middle
to put the metal accessories.
OK.
Next, we will do the belt part
by re-applying a panel as the belt part.
OK.
Then we will do the hole in the middle.
For the hole in the middle,
we can draw some circles with the inner circle.
OK.
For the hole in the middle,
we can draw some circles with the inner circle.
After drawing the circle,
we can re-apply it.
because we do the circle in the middle,
which is the position of the gas eye,
this thing is called the gas eye.
This thing.
There are many ways to do the gas eye.
In this case,
the simplest way is to do it with a plate.
You draw a circle,
draw an inner circle,
and then draw a bigger inner circle,
to form a circle.
There is another way.
You can use the method I used in my video.
First,
we cut the three round panels in the middle.
After that,
we apply a new fabric to it.
This is the previous fabric.
Apply a new fabric.
For the new fabric,
we set its transparency to 0.
So it's like a hole in the middle.
But in fact,
there is a panel in the middle.
What's the benefit of this?
That is,
if your belt is tight,
and there is a problem of stretching and deformation,
then this round,
not a round,
this round panel can also be limited,
so that the hole is not severely deformed.
Can you understand?
So sometimes,
we will use this transparent panel
to do something that you can't see.
For example,
the chest.
Don't make it too big.
Or control the direction of some tight clothes
in the hole position.
Because if there is no panel,
if there is no sewing line,
it will open like this.
So we will replace it with a round panel here.
OK.
As long as everyone understands.
After that,
if you dig here,
you can't put a button.
But now we have a transparent panel.
You can put a copy on the transparent panel
or put a button.
So here,
we can put a button on this panel.
Then,
in the digital editor,
change the type of this button
to the button type of the eye.
Look,
give it a new button type.
Here,
we change the type first,
then change its value.
OK, now we have the eye again.
Then we turn off its conflict.
Otherwise,
it has a conflict with the panel.
Because we want this eye
to be embedded in the panel.
So we have to turn off its conflict.
And turn the length of the line directly into the negative number.
Are these rings embedded in the belt?
And it is very stable.
Because it is attached to the transparent panel.
So this is another way we have.
How to do it.
So we learn knowledge step by step.
We first know that the button is here.
Here,
we can change its button attribute.
Then we can use the move button tool.
After selecting the button,
turn off the conflict of the button.
So that it will not have
the problem of instability and movement.
Then,
through the length of the negative line,
the button can be embedded in the panel.
Understand?
So everyone must support our live broadcast.
Because I am in the process of preparing for the live broadcast.
I will look at the questions of everyone in the group.
I was preparing for the live broadcast.
At that time,
the problem of preparing this transparent panel
is that there are friends in the group.
He doesn't know how to do this gas eye.
He said,
Hey,
why can't I add a button after I dig a hole?
Because the center of the button must be attached to the panel.
So we have to replace it with a transparent panel.
Instead of digging this circle directly.
Understand?
Then we,
you see,
because we have always been frozen panels,
we didn't simulate it together.
Then we are in the middle.
In the process,
it is best to untie it
and then simulate it as a whole.
To prevent it.
After that,
we change the action again.
If you simulate it directly at once,
it may be between the panel and the panel.
Well,
there will be conflict thickness,
and the effect of those compressing forces will cause instability.
So I usually untie all the panels
in the middle.
Then simulate them.
See if there is any instability.
For example,
just write here.
It has an unstable place.
I will set its level,
and then simulate it.